Guide to the Linus Wilson Darling papers 1859-1906
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Papers
1855-1910
Oregon Historical Society, Davies Family Research Library
Mss 129
Darling, Linus Wilson, 1855-1910
.5 cubic feet 2 boxes
Papers of a farmer, surveyor, merchant, lawyer, and justice of the peace in Gilliam County, Oregon. Includes correspondence, diary, financial records, notes on farming, scale drawings and plans for farm structures and houses, and genealogical materials.
Biographical Note
Linus Wilson Darling was a farmer, surveyor, general store owner, druggist, lawyer, and justice of the peace in Gilliam County, Oregon (Lonerock, Condon).
Papers include: Correspondence (1880-1893); diary (1883-1890; 1897); financial accounts (1859, 1876 and 1884-1887); school exercises; essays; notes on farming, surveying, and public construction; scale drawings and plans for farm structures and houses; genealogical materials regarding the Darling-Pauling family; newspaper clippings; and memorabilia.
The collection is arranged in four volumes.
Researchers are requested to use preservation copies of the materials, found in Box 2 of the collection.
The collection is open to the public.
Lucie Jenkins, Jan. 9, 1973, Accession 12424.
P. M. Stephenson, June 24, 1982, Accession 15989.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Darling, Linus Wilson, 1855-1910--Correspondence; Darling, Linus Wilson, 1855-1910--Diaries; Darling family; Paulin family
Pioneers--Oregon--Gilliam County--Correspondence; Pioneers--Oregon--Gilliam County--Diaries; Frontier and pioneer life--Oregon--Gilliam County; Farmers--Oregon--Gilliam County--Correspondence; Farmers--Oregon--Gilliam County--Diaries; Businessmen--Oregon--Gilliam County--Correspondence; Businessmen--Oregon--Gilliam County--Diaries; Justices of the peace--Oregon--Gilliam County--Correspondence; Justices of the peace--Oregon--Gilliam County--Diaries; Justice, administration of--Oregon--Gilliam County
Lonerock (Or.)--Description and travel; Condon (Or.)--Description and travel
Oregon; Pacific Northwest History; Diaries; Architectural Drawings; Business, Industry, and Labor; City and Town Life; Agriculture
Clippings; Diaries; Letters; Architectural drawings
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Volume 1, 1859-1876 (Box 1)
  - Accounts
    - 1876 Jan. (Page 1-4, 7-9)
    - 1876 Feb. (Page 10-12, 70-71)
    - 1876 Mar. (Page 13-15, 72-74)
    - 1876 Apr. (Page 16-20)
    - 1859 Mar. (Page 67-69)
    - undated (Page 79-80)
  - Arithmetic problems, undated (Page 29-30, 32-33, 50-58, 65-66, 75, 92, 108-109)
  - English exercises, undated (Page 37-46, 82, 85-91, 110-124)
  - Letters, articles (some of them drafts), undated (Page 49, 100-103, 105)
  - Notes on planetary system, undated (Page 60-61)
- Volume 2, 1883-1894 (Box 1)
  - Accounts, 1884-1886 (Page 90-113, 238)
  - Articles, undated (Page 3, 7, 30-31)
  - Clippings
    - 1883 (Page 3)
    - 1884 (Page 27, 34-35)
    - 1894 (Page 194, 196-197)
  - Diary
    - 1883 Feb.-Oct. (Page 10-26)
    - 1883 Oct.-1884 Oct. (Page 41-89)
    - 1884 (Page 140-153)
    - 1885 (Page 154-184)
    - 1886 (Page 184-185, 116-139, 232-235)
  - Marriages performed by Darling, 1882-1884 (Page 28)
  - Notes concerning nomenclature of Lone Rock, Tutuila, and Butter Creek, undated (Page 8-9)
  - Notes concerning nomenclature of Hangman's Creek, undated (Page 29)
  - Surveys, undated (Page 187-193, 203-230)
- Volume 3, 1886-1897 (Box 1)
  - Accounts
    - 1886 (Page 128)
    - 1887 (Page 2-11, 121-125)
    - Re: building of drugstore, 1887 (Page 40-41)
  - Diary
    - 1887 (Page 12-39)
    - 1888-1890 (Page 42-50)
    - 1897 (Page 61-105)
  - List of letters written and orders placed, 1887 (Page 126-127)
  - Notes concerning construction of a windmill, undated (Page 59-60)
  - Scale drawings and notes
    - Plans for a grain house, undated (Page 52)
    - Plans for an ice house, undated (Page 53, 56)
    - Farming notes, undated (Page 54)
    - Plans for a barn, undated (Page 57)
    - Plans for a house, undated (Page 58)
- Volume 4, 1880-1906 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1880-1893
  - Drafts and manuscripts of articles, undated
  - Clippings relating to Linus Darling and his family, undated
  - Newspaper advertisement, ca. 1893
  - Programs, 1892-1906
  - Surveys, undated
  - General notes and clippings regarding farming, undated
  - Poems--clippings, articles and manuscripts, undated
  - Clippings and papers relating to elections, undated
- Preservation photostatic copies (Box 2)
  - Contents of original vol. 1 (Volume 1)
    Includes accounts, letters, and articles
  - Contents of original vol. 2 (Volume 2)
    Includes accounts, diary, farm notes, surveys
  - Contents of original vol. 3 (Volume 3)
    Includes accounts, diary, construction notes
  - Contents of original vol. 4 (Volume 4)
    Includes correspondence, articles, genealogy, newspaper clippings, surveys, and political tickets